

Technologist

jamesdavidmoffet.com

jim@jamesdavidmoffet.com

in jamesdavidmoffet

about

As a technologist, I am obsessed with understanding the human mechanisms by which technology can deliver us into an alternative future. As a researcher, I have learned to temper this obsession, harnessing critical theory and a range of research and management techniques that help me to redirect the internal inertia of established organizations and to find room to apply systems-level, user-centered thinking to the awesome challenge of improving people's lives.

education

2016 - 2018

Harvard University Graduate School of Design

Master's Degree Design Studies in Technology

SKIIS

Product Management User Research UI/UX Design Software Engineering Machine Learning R, SPSS, Python, Torch Hardware Engineering Public Speaking

work experience

SEIU International

2009 - 2014 Portland, OR, USA Senior Data Product Manager Led team that designed and developed a cloud-hosted financial and membership data system handling 25M records, 50 corp. partners and \$5M revenue. Developed long-term organizational data, design and procurement strategy.

Fulbright Fellow

2015 - 2016 Budapest, HU Lecturer / Researcher Researched public design thinking education at the Center for Media, Data and Society in Budapest. Piloted OpenLab workshops teaching UXR, interface design and tech prototyping for public projects out of FabLab Budapest.

MIT Community Innovators Lab

2016 - 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA

Research Manager Managed a democratic capacity mapping and toolbuilding project for the MIT Community Innovators lab. Oversaw research labor, designed and engineered a democratic capacity mapping and organizational partnership tool.

Civic Tech Fellow

Summer 2017 Cambridge, MA, USA CivTech Product Manager Developed civic technology for the City of Cambridge, focusing on easy to deploy open source citizen analytics apps and consulting with GoINVO on the MA SNAP application redesign.

2017 - 2018 Cambridge, MA, USA

OutVote.io & Commit.vote - Founder / Director of Product Founded civic tech startup COMM!T, a tool for peer-enforced smart contracts to drive civic participation. Acquired by OutVote civic networking app Nov. 2017. Currently owning product for a firm with 10 enterprise clients.